Department of Urban and Environmental Policy and Planning Records UA090
Tufts Archival Research Center
- Syllabi, 1978 -- 2014; UA090.000015; 2.5 Linear Feet 2 record cartons and 1 document box
  - UEP 252: Cities in Space, Place and Time, circa 2008; UA090.000073 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - UEP 253: Financial Analysis and Management, Spring 2000 -- Spring 2009; UA090.000074 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - UEP 254: Quantitative Reasoning, Spring 1995 -- Fall 2013; UA090.000075 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - UEP 255: Field Projects, Spring 2001 -- Spring 2009; UA090.000076 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - UEP 256: Program Evaluation, Fall 1999 -- Spring 2009; UA090.000077 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - UEP 257: Structural Determinants of Health, 1988; UA090.000078 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - UEP 258: Intermediate Quantitative Reasoning, Spring 2005 -- Fall 2010; UA090.000079 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - UEP 258: Intermediate Quantitative Reasoning, Fall 2006; UA090.000080 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - UEP 261: Community Development, Spring 2002 -- Spring 2008; UA090.000081 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - UEP 262: Environmental Economics, Spring 1990 -- Spring 1999; UA090.000082 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - UEP 263: Natural Resource Policy, Fall 1987 -- Fall 2007; UA090.000083 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - UEP 264-01: Green Urban Design and Place-Making, Spring 2009; UA090.000084 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - UEP 264: Hazardous Materials Policy and Regulations, 1989 -- 1999; UA090.000085 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - UEP 265: Corporate Management of Environmental Issues, Spring 1993 -- Fall 2008; UA090.000086 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - UEP 265: Internship Seminar, Summer 1981; UA090.000087 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - UEP 266: Environmental Policy Research, Spring 1993 -- Spring 2002; UA090.000088 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - UEP 267: Environmental Policy Analysis, Fall 1997 -- Spring 2006; UA090.000089 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - UEP 267: Analytical Requirements of Environmental Regulation, Spring 1987 -- Spring 2006; UA090.000090 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - UEP 268: Neighborhood Planning, Spring 1984; UA090.000091 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - UEP 269: Seminar in Environmental Regulation, Spring 1982 -- Spring 1984; UA090.000092 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - UEP 270: Social Ownership and Community Control, Fall 1986 -- Fall 1995; UA090.000093 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - UEP 271: Community Economic Development, Fall 1988 -- Fall 2008; UA090.000094 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - UEP 272: Real Estate Development and Finance, circa Fall 2000 -- Fall 2001; UA090.000095 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - UEP 273: Real Estate Development and Finance, Fall 1985 -- Fall 1991; UA090.000096 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - UEP 273: Nonprofit Organizations and Public Policy, Fall 1994 -- Fall 2010; UA090.000097 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - UEP 275: International Environmental Policy and Development, Spring 1986 -- Spring 1990; UA090.000098 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - UEP 277: Thesis Seminar in Environmental Policy, Fall 1997 -- Fall 2009; UA090.000099 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - UEP 278: Environmental Justice, Spring 2000 -- Fall 2008; UA090.000100 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - UEP 279: Water Resources Policy and Watershed Management, Fall 1990 -- Fall 2008; UA090.000101 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - UEP 280: Current Issues in Environmental Policy, Fall 1998 -- Fall 2002; UA090.000102 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - UEP 281: Chemicals, Health, and Environment, Spring 1997 -- Spring 2003; UA090.000103 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - UEP 282: Advanced Seminar in Housing and Community Development, Fall 1986 -- Fall 1992; UA090.000104 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - UEP 283: Environmental Communication and Education, Spring 2000 -- Fall 2003; UA090.000105 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - UEP 284: Developing Sustainable Communities, Spring 2001 -- Spring 2009; UA090.000106 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - UEP 285: Advanced Seminar: Urban Social Policy, Fall 1992 -- Fall 2006; UA090.000107 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - UEP 285: Work and Working in Policy, Planning, and Society, Fall 2009; UA090.000108 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - UEP 286: Environmental Ethics, Fall 2002 -- Spring 2009; UA090.000109 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - UEP 287: Environmental Sociology, Fall 1987 -- Spring 2008; UA090.000110 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - UEP 288: Reflections on Public Policy Practice, Fall 2002 -- Fall 2011; UA090.000111 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - UEP 289: Integrative Seminar, Spring 2003 -- Spring 2004; UA090.000112 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - UEP 289: Integrative Seminar, Spring 2007 -- Spring 2008; UA090.000113 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - UEP 290: Public Policy of Water, Spring 2005; UA090.000114 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - UEP 292B: Effective Working Board, 1991; UA090.000115 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - UEP 292E: Seminar on Environmental Politics and Policy, Spring 1988; UA090.000116 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - UEP 293-02: Transportation Planning, Fall 2006; UA090.000117 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - UEP 293-02: Poverty, Fall 2014; UA090.000118 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - UEP 293A: Land Policy and Real Estate Development and Finance, Fall 1997 -- Fall 2001; UA090.000119 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - UEP 293B: Ecological Applications for Environmental Management, Fall 1991 -- Fall 2001; UA090.000120 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - UEP 293A: Introduction to Environmental Policy, Fall 1996; UA090.000121 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - UEP 293C: Advanced Seminar in Social Policy, circa 2000; UA090.000122 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - UEP 293C: Advanced Seminar: Feminist Approaches to Urban and Environmental Policy, Fall 1992; UA090.000123 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - UEP 293E: Principles of Environmental Management, Fall 1991 -- Fall 1993; UA090.000124 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - UEP 293E: The Urban Environment: Policy, Planning and Law, Fall 1999 -- Fall 2004; UA090.000125 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - UEP 293E: Economic Principles and Tools of Environmental Management, Fall 1995; UA090.000126 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - UEP 293F: Recycling Solid Waste, Fall 1999; UA090.000127 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - UEP 293G: The Urban Environment: Selected Problems, Solutions and Policy, Fall 1993 -- Spring 1996; UA090.000128 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - UEP 293I: Policies for Sustainable Development, Fall 1994; UA090.000129 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - UEP 293J: Environment and the Food Supply, Fall 1995 -- Fall 2002; UA090.000130 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - UEP 293L: Water Resources Policy and Watershed Management, Fall 2000 -- Fall 2001; UA090.000131 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - CD 243M/UEP 293M: Seminars on Families and Work, Fall 2002 -- Fall 2003; UA090.000132 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - UEP 294: Community Control in Boston, Spring 1991; UA090.000133 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - UEP 294: Building Community Support, circa 1990; UA090.000134 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - UEP 294-01: Physical Planning and Design, Spring 2007; UA090.000135 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - UEP 294-03: Politics of Sustainable Cities, Spring 2008 -- Spring 2009; UA090.000136 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - UEP 294-05: Introduction to Remote Sensing, Spring 2012; UA090.000137 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - UEP 294-06: Qualitative Skills for Planning and Public Policy, Spring 2009; UA090.000138 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - UEP 294-16: Environmental Health for Policy and Planning, Fall 2012; UA090.000139 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - UEP 294-18: Jobs that Work: Designing Employment Strategies for Today's Communities, Spring 2012; UA090.000140 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - UEP 294-19: Anchor Institutions and Community Revitalization, Fall 2014; UA090.000141 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - UEP 294A: Future of Philanthropy, Fall 2002 -- Spring 2005; UA090.000142 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - UEP 294A: Wetlands Assessment and Management, 1988 December -- Spring 1992; UA090.000143 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - UEP 294A: Public Policy on Management and Conservation of Natural Resources, 1988 December -- Spring 1992; UA090.000144 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - UEP 294BC: Local Government Finance, Summer 2013; UA090.000145 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - UEP 294C: Sustainable Development, Spring 1990 -- Spring 1992; UA090.000146 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - UEP 294C: Seminar in Community Development Strategies, Spring 2000; UA090.000147 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - UEP 294C: New Management Literature, circa 1990; UA090.000148 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - UEP 294D: Seminar on Theory and Politics of Poverty, Spring 1990; UA090.000149 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - UEP 294D: National Urban Policy, Spring 1994 -- Spring 1996; UA090.000150 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - UEP 294D: Urban and Growth Policy, Spring 2000; UA090.000151 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - UEP 294D: Ecological Applications for Environmental Management, circa 1998; UA090.000152 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - UEP 294E: Equity and the Environment, Spring 1996; UA090.000153 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - UEP 294E: Ecology Based Policy Making, Spring 1996 -- Spring 1998; UA090.000154 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - UEP 294F: Community and Environmental Advocacy, Spring 1996 -- Spring 1998; UA090.000155 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - UEP 294F: Pollution Prevention and the Law, circa 1994; UA090.000156 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - UEP 294F: Probability and Statistics for Policy and Planning, circa 1997; UA090.000157 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - UEP 294F: Mediation and the Resolution of Disputes, Spring 1992; UA090.000158 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - UEP 294H: Seminar on the Changing Nature of Work, Spring 1998; UA090.000159 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - UEP 294H: Environmental Pollution: Selected Problems, Spring 1994; UA090.000160 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - UEP 294J: Environmental Justice and Sustainable Communities, Spring 1999; UA090.000161 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - UEP 294J: Class, Race, and the Environment, Spring 1994; UA090.000162 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - UEP 294J: Selected Topics in Ecology and Resource Management, circa 1994; UA090.000163 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - UEP 294K: Integrated Assessment of Fresh Water Resources, Spring 1999 -- Spring 2004; UA090.000164 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - UEP 294M/PS 100: Seminar in Leadership for Active Citizenship, Spring 2000 -- Spring 2001; UA090.000165 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Feminism and Poverty in the U.S., Fall 1997; UA090.000166 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Mass Bay Marine Studies Consortium - Water: Planning for the Future, Spring 1992; UA090.000167 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - UEP 104: Science in the Modern Age, circa 1990; UA090.000168 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - PS 113: Power and Politics in America, Fall 1989; UA090.000169 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - UEP 191A/EXP 76F: Politics of Public Policy, Fall 1988 -- Fall 1991; UA090.000170 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - UEP 194G: Environmental Decision Making, Spring 1994 -- Spring 1995; UA090.000171 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - UEP 192A: Civil Rights Movement, Spring 1989; UA090.000172 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - UEP 203: Seminar on Interest Groups, Fall 1988 -- Fall 1990; UA090.000173 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - PS 204: Citizen Participation and Democracy, Spring 1990 -- Spring 1993; UA090.000174 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - NUTR/UEP 224: Environment and Food Supply, Fall 1996 -- Spring 2000; UA090.000175 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Economics 235: Latin America's Economy, 1999; UA090.000176 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - NUTR/UEP 243: Institutions of Agriculture, Spring 2000; UA090.000177 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - NUTR/UEP 244: Food and Environmental Risk Communication, Fall 1998; UA090.000178 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - UEP 252: Methods for Planning and Policy Analysis, circa 1980; UA090.000179 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Old syllabi, 1986 -- 1989; UA090.000180 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    Miscellaneous Urban and Environmental Policy and Planning course syllabi.
- 2022 accessions, 1971 -- 2013; UA090.000181; 1 Linear Feet 1 record carton
  This series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
  Transferred by Laurel Williams, Administrative Assistant for Urban and Environmental Policy and Planning, 2022, accession UA-2023-036.
  This series is arranged in received order.
  This series contains publications, department files, and Overseeing Committee meeting minutes related to the development and administration of the Department of Urban and Environmental Policy and Planning (UEP) at Tufts. The bulk of the materials date from 1971-2006.
  - UEP program guides, 1978 -- 1999; UA090.000182 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Certificate program brochure, 1996 -- 1998; UA090.000183 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Tufts info sheet in Peterson's, 1980 -- 1998; UA090.000184 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Tufts commencement brochures, 1996 -- 2001; UA090.000185 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Student reference booklet, 1991; UA090.000186 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    20 years from date of creation.
  - 5th Annual Environmental Management Institute, 1992 -- 1998; UA090.000187 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Misc. articles, 1994 -- 1998; UA090.000188 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Tuftonia with article on UEP's 25th, 1999; UA090.000189 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Tufts brochures, 1987; UA090.000190 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Archives, 1993 -- 2001; UA090.000191 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - UEP pamphlets, 1980 -- 2003; UA090.000192 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Memos, 1979 -- 1980; UA090.000193 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Accounting, 1979 -- 1980; UA090.000194 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Concepts, circa 1979 -- 1980; UA090.000195 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Personnel, 1979 -- 1980; UA090.000196 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Info bank, 1979 -- 1980; UA090.000197 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Seminar, circa 1980; UA090.000198 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Brochures and pamphlets, circa 1983 -- 2006; UA090.000199 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Brown house forum and original OTW's, 1990; UA090.000200 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Management and Community Development Institute, 1980 -- 2000; UA090.000201 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Department newsletters, 1983 -- 2005; UA090.000202 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Public forums, Mystic River, 1974 -- 1975; UA090.000203 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Urban program development, 1971 -- 1973; UA090.000204 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Overseeing committee meetings, 1976 -- 1977; UA090.000205 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Overseeing committee meetings, 1975 -- 1976; UA090.000206 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    75 years from date of creation.
  - Overseeing committee meetings, 1974 -- 1975; UA090.000207 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Overseeing committee meetings, 1973 -- 1974; UA090.000208 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Admission data, 1973 -- 1974; UA090.000209 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Overseeing committee, 1973 -- 2013; UA090.000210 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Program newsletters, 1973 -- 1986; UA090.000211 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Program guides, 1987 -- 1997; UA090.000212 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Brochures and program guides, 1980 -- 2006; UA090.000213 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Graduate school information, 1973 -- 1978; UA090.000214 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Boston Architectural Center, 1975; UA090.000215 (Box 1, Folder 34)